Guide to the Edward S. Goldstein: Jewish Labor Committee Research Files WAG.232
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: Subject Files, 1933-1985.
  - Minutes: Panel on New York City Civil Rights Affairs, 1953-1956 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Missouri: Defeat of "Right to Work" Measure, 2978 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Morgenstern, Herman: Translated Articles from The Day, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Muravchik, Emanuel, 1949-1967 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Murray, Philip: Bust Presented to Reuther, Walter, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP) and Communism, 1949-1954 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians (NABET) Strike, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - National Black Political Convention: Gary, Indiana, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - National Community Relations Advisory Council: Committee on Class Approach, 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - National Jewish Welfare Board: JLC Participation, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - National Organizations Committee, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - National Staff Conference, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - National Staff Conference: Transcript One, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - National Staff Conference: Transcript Two, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - National Staff Conference: Transcript Three, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - National Trade Union Committee for Racial Justice, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - National Trade Union Council for Human Rights, 1955-1957 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - National Trade Union Council for Human Rights, 1958-1966 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - National Trade Union Council: Lists, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - National Trade Union Council: Minutes, 1956-1959 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - National Trade Union Council: Minutes, 1960-1964 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Neue Volkszeitung: Aid to, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Neustadt: "The Unending Task," Notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - New Haven, Connecticut, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - New Left and the JLC, 1966-1970 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - New York Activists: JLC, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - New York JLC, 1953-1978 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Niebuhr, Reinhold, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Olgin, M.: Articles on the JLC, 1937-1938 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Overseas Activities: Aid, 1937-1977 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Palestine, 1946-1948 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Palestine: Bi-National State Proposal, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Palestine: JLC Policy, 1940-1941 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Palestine: Left Poale Zion, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Parkchester Housing Campaign, 1952-1955 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Parkchester Housing Campaign: Robinson, Jackie, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Pat, Jacob, 1939-1966 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Pat, Jacob: "Problems of Jewish Rehabilitation", 1945 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Pat, Jacob: "Story of the JLC", 1948 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Pearl Harbor: Response to, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Personnel Practices: JLC, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Philadelphia: Freedom Budget, Rustin, B., etc., 1967 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Pittsburgh, 1954-1990 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Pittsburgh Courier vs. JLC, 1959-1961 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Poale Agudath Israel and Green, William, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Point of View: General, 1962-1968 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Poland, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Poland: Aid from JLC and Joint Distribution Committee, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Poland: Anti-Semitism, etc., 1946 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Police: Civilian Review Board, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Polish Government in Exile, 1941-1945 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Polish Underground: Aid Sent, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Post-War Reconstruction and International Labor, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Powell, Adam Clayton, Jr., undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Prague Trials: JLC Mass Meeting: Speeches, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Presidential Appointments: JLC Recommendations for, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Presidents Conference, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Presidents Conference and Council of Jewish Organizations: JLC View, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Program: JLC, 1965-1973 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Public Relations Department: Godsen, Joseph, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Publications of the JLC, 1946-1968 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Publicity Materials, 1950, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Radosh, Ronald, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Radio Work: JLC, 1948-1955 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Dawidowicz, S.: Comment on JLC Terminology in Israel, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 50A)
  - Refugee Children, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Refugees: Gauss, J., undated (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Regional Conference: JLC, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Relations between the JLC and Other Jewish Communal Organizations, 1940-1963 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Relief Activity: Europe, 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Reparations, 1949-1969 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Reparations: Austria, 1952-1955 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Reparations: Germany, 1951-1953 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Report: Civil Rights Work, undated (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Report: Meeting on Situation in Europe, 1934-1937 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - "Report on Freedom" (WEVD radio), undated (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Reports, undated (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Reports, 1934-1948 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Reports, 1949-1959 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Reports, 1961-1977 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Reports and Resolutions, 1949-1977 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Rescue Work and Aid to Displaced Persons, 1940-1953 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Research Committee: Post-War Problems, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Resolutions, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Reuther, Walter, 1952-1955 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Rheinmetall Protest, 1948-1967 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Right-Wing Extremists, 1963-1965 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Romania, 1956-1959 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1942-1944 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Rosenwald, Lessing J., 1951-1953 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Russian Solidarist Movement, 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Rustin, Bayard, 1961-1978 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - "Salt of the Earth" and JLC, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - San Francisco, 1957-1958 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Schmeling Boycott, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Schools: Labor Material on Public Schools, 1949-1960 (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - Schools: Teachers Strike, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Schwartz, Pinchos, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Selma-Montgomery March: JLC Role, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Seminar Discussion Group: JLC, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Seminar on Jewish Affairs, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Seminars: Anti-Communism, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Sessions, John A.: "Jews in the American Labor Movement", 1975 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Shanghai: Fiszman, Iosl, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Shanker, Albert, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Shapiro, Elliott, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Shapiro, Elliott: Intolerance, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Shapiro, Elliott: "Jewish Problem in the American Trade Union Press", 1945 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Shapiro, Elliott: "Jewish Problem in the American Trade Union Press", 1946 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Shapiro, Elliott: "Jewish Problem in the American Trade Union Press", 1947 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Shapiro, Elliott: "Jewish Problem in the American Trade Union Press", 1948 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Shapiro, Elliott: "Jewish Problem in the American Trade Union Press", 1949 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Shapiro, Elliott: "Studies of Labor Reports", 1949-1950 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Shapiro, Elliott: Study of Labor Press, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Sheinkman, Jacob, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Sherman, Charles Bezalel: "Bund, Galuth Nationalism, Yiddishism", 1958 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Sherman, Charles Bezalel: "Jewish Community Relations Reappraised", 1966 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Slaiman, Donald, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Socialists/Social Democrats and the JLC, 1947-1977 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Southern Project: JLC, 1958-1966 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Southern Trade Unions and Field Office Project, 1956-1968 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Southwest Jewish Press: on JLC, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Soviet Jewry, 1946-1971 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Soviet Jewry: American Jewish Conference Questionnaire, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Soviet Jewry: Madison Square Garden Rally, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Soviet Yiddish Writers, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Soviet Yiddish Writers: Mass Protest (JLC), 1956 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Staff Conference, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Staff (JLC): Office and Professional Employees International Union (OPEIU), Local 153 Agreement, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Staff Salaries, undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Stalin-Hitler Pact: JLC Statement, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Stevenson, Adlai, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Structure of the JLC, 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Student Labor Project, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee and Anti-Semitism, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Tabachinsky, Benjamin, 1941-1967 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Tercentenary: Exhibit, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Twenty-fifth Anniversary, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Tyler, Gus, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Underground Work, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Union of Russian Jews, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - United Farm Workers: Manischewitz and Grape Boycott, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - United Hatters, Cap, and Millinery Workers Union, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - United Hebrew Trades, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - United Nations: Jewish Organizations at Founding, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - United States Congress: Committee on Communist Aggression, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - U.S. Department of Labor: Bureau of Apprenticeship and Training, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - U.S. Department of State, Office of Public Affairs: Organization Information Sheet, 1946-1949 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - U.S. Senate Labor Sub-Committee: Sheinkman Testimony, undated (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Vaad Hahatzalah, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Vietnam War: Labor Support for, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Vladeck, Baruch Charney: on Palestine, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Vlasovist Movement, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - War Assets Administration, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Ward, Martin: JLC Award, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Warsaw Ghetto Commemorations, 1988-1995 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Warsaw Ghetto: Dubinsky, D. and Carey, J. Broadcast to the Fighters in the Ghetto, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Warsaw Ghetto Uprising, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Washington, DC, 1954-1963 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Washington, DC: Fundraising Letter: Goldberg, Arthur, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Weinberg, Joseph, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Weisberg, Sam: Cleveland, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Welfare Funds: Allocations, 1949-1965 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Welfare Funds: Grants to JLC, 1939-1972 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Welfare Funds: JLC Relations with, undated (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - White Paper on Palestine, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Wilkins, Roy, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - William Green Library, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Wishengrad, Morton: "Unfinished Business," Radio Play, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - Wolchok, Samuel, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - Woll, Matthew, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 75)
  - Women's Division, 1947-1977 (Box 5, Folder 76)
  - Woocher, Jonathan S.: "Civil Judaism in the United States", undated (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - Worcester, Mass: Civil Rights, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 78)
  - "Working Class Majority," New Yorker, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 79)
  - Workmen's Circle and the JLC, 1948-1977 (Box 5, Folder 80)
  - Workmen's Circle Division, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 81)
  - Workmen's Circle: Funding, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 82)
  - World Conference for Yiddish Culture, undated (Box 5, Folder 83)
  - World Jewish Congress and the JLC, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 84)
  - Yabloff, Herman (Hyman Yablonik): European Concert Tour, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 85)
  - Yiddish Culture, 1949-1967 (Box 5, Folder 86)
  - Young Circle League of America, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 87)
  - Youngstown, Ohio, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 88)
  - Youth Marches for Integration, 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 89)
  - Zaritsky, Max, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 90)
  - Zimmerman, Charles S., 1947-1968 (Box 5, Folder 91)
  - Zimmerman, Charles: "Class Approach", 1948 (Box 5, Folder 92)
  - Zionism and the JLC, 1937-1961 (Box 5, Folder 93)
  - Zionism: General, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 94)
  - Zionists: Conflict with Jewish Labor Bund in Displaced Persons Camps, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 95)
  - Zukerman, Jacob T., 1967 (Box 5, Folder 96)
  - Zygielbojm, Arthur: Telegram re: Support for Underground, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 97)
- Series III: Oversized Item (Photocopied Scrapbook), 1942.
  - Clippings Scrapbook (JLC) [photocopy], 1942 (Box 6, Folder 1)